(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ららーいおん！ ホロライブ5期生 獅白ぼたん、です！
La-la-lion! Hololive 5th gen Shishiro Botan here!
ということで今日は、ねぽらぼアイドル衣装... ちょっと噛んじゃったけど、
So today, the "NePoLaBo" idol outfits... Whoops, I tripped over my words,
ということで、みんなのアイドル衣装を見てきたんですけれども、
but anyway, we've seen everyone's idol outfits,
ししろももちろんあります！
and of course, Shishiro has one too!
ただね、ちょっとね、時間があるんで、おしらせも踏まえ、
However, since we have a little time, I have an announcement to make,
ちょっとやりたいことがあったので、ちょっとやらせていただきます！
and there's something else I'd like to do, so I'll be doing that!
ということで、さっそくこちらのコーナー行ってみましょう！
So, let's jump right into this segment!
「ぼたんクッキング」！
"Botan Cooking!"
ということでね、こちらのコーナーではわたくし、獅白ぼたんが、
In this segment, I, Shishiro Botan,
秘密のレシピをちょっとお届けして作るというコーナーになってます。
will be sharing and making something from a secret recipe.
何ができるかは完成してからのお楽しみということで、
What will it be? You'll have to wait until it's finished to find out!
今日紹介するレシピはこちら！ ドン！
The recipe I'm introducing today is this one! Ta-da!
???のレシピ
??? Recipe
さあ、この段階では何ができるかちょっとわからないんで、みんな想像してみてください。
You might not be able to tell what it is at this stage, so try to guess!
じゃあさっそく作っていきましょう。
Well then, let's get started!
何ができるかな？ 調理開始！ ドンドコドンドコ...
I wonder what it'll be? Let's start cooking! (Drumroll)
まず、バターをポイッといれます。
First, the butter... plop! Put it in.
このね、ちょっとね、あったかくしたのをコネコネしていってください。
Give this slightly warmed butter a good knead.
ほぐしていきます。そしてそこに次、粉糖を投げ入れ。
Keep breaking it down. Next, toss in the powdered sugar.
混ぜていきます。コネコネします。
Mix it all together. Give it a good knead.
で、卵はね、少しずつ、だいたい4回ぐらいにちょっと分けて入れてください。
As for the egg, add it in about four parts, little by little.
じゃないとね、ちょっと分離しちゃうので。
Otherwise, it might separate.
なじませてよく、グニャグニャしていきます。
Blend it well... squish, squish.
グニャグニャ...
Squishy, squishy...
そしてね、次、薄力粉とブラックココアを入れます。
Next, add the cake flour and black cocoa.
さあ、何ができるんでしょう？ こちら入れてから
Now, what will it be? Once that's in,
ざっくり混ぜていきます。
give it a rough mix.
生地がね、できるイメージで、ザクザクと混ぜていってください。
Imagine you're making a dough as you mix it.
ちょっといい感じに固まってきたら、
Once it starts to come together nicely,
生地を手でこねていきます。コネコネコネコネ...
knead the dough with your hands. Knead, knead, knead...
そして、生地を伸ばしていきます。おら、おら！
And then, roll out the dough. Hup, hup!
ということで、伸びました。さあ、およ？
And there it is, all rolled out! Oh?
ここで、何か型が出てきた！ お、何だ、見覚えのある型だ。
A cookie cutter has appeared! Wait, I've seen this shape before...
いや、何が出来上がるんでしょうね？ ちょっと楽しみですね。さあ、切っていきます。
I wonder what it'll turn into? I'm excited! Let's cut them out.
そして、180度余熱したオーブンで焼いていきます。
Then, bake them in an oven preheated to 180 degrees.
いいですね。なんか、お前らに似た物体がオーブンで焼かれていく姿をご覧ください。
Looking good. Please enjoy the sight of things that look like you being baked in the oven.
ハハハ！ 何ができるんだろう？ 楽しみだね。
Haha! I wonder what they'll be? Can't wait!
お、そして、ちょっとおしゃれしましょう。
Oh! Now for some finishing touches.
焼き上がった生地に、下地をね、ヌリヌリしていきましょう。
Apply the base icing to the baked cookies.
ちなみにね、塗った直後はちょっと、あの、乾いてないので、
By the way, it's wet right after applying,
少し乾燥する時間も置いてください。
so please give it some time to dry.
さあ、乾いたものがこちら。そしたら...
Alright, here it is dried! Next...
お、目を描き、口も描き。
Draw the eyes... and the mouth.
なんか見たことある顔だな。なんだこの顔。
That face looks familiar... what is it?
さあ、もうここまで来たらわかりますよね。
I'm sure you can tell by now!
さあ、最後はししろとお揃いの、首飾りの模様をつけたら、
Lastly, add the pattern from Shishiro's necklace...
完成！ ジャジャーン！
and it's complete! Ta-da!
ということで、SSRBのアイシングクッキーです！ バリエーション3種。
Behold, the SSRB Icing Cookies! Three variations.
これね、マシュマロもいれてます。
I've also used marshmallows in these.
ブラックココアの味、抹茶の味、プレーンの味。可愛いね、いいね。
Black cocoa flavor, matcha flavor, and plain flavor. So cute, right?
ついに、オホホ！
Finally... haha!
ついに、SSRBも食べられる時代。希望小売価格、1個 500円。
The day has come where you can eat SSRBs! Suggested retail price: 500 yen each.
お買い求めください。ありがとうございます！
Please consider buying them! Thank you very much!
ということでね。
Anyway...
SSRB... ちなみに、このSSRBのアイシングクッキーね、作ったんですけど、
I made these SSRB icing cookies,
ちょっとね、実際に購入はできないんで、ちょっとごめんなさいね。
but unfortunately, they aren't actually for sale. Sorry about that!
その代わり今日、現物は用意してるんですよ。
But instead, I've prepared the real thing today!
ほら！ ああ！ お前らついに...
Look! Oh! You guys finally...
お前らついに、3Dになったのか！ ハハハ！
You guys finally became 3D? Haha!
可愛いね、現物用意しました、こちら！
How cute! I've brought the real thing. Here they are!
できました！
They're finished!
そしてそして、なんと何と！ お知らせがあります。
And wait, there's more! I have an announcement.
今日作ったSSRBじゃないんですけれども、
It's not about the ones I made today,
別のSSRBがグッズになります！
but different SSRBs are becoming merchandise!
ということで、こちら。ジャジャーン！
So, here they are! Ta-da!
獅白ぼたん100万人記念グッズ、いよいよ発売ということで、ありがとうございます。
Shishiro Botan's 1 million subscriber milestone goods are finally on sale! Thank you so much!
100万人になったのがちょっと、去年なんですけれども、
I reached 1 million subscribers last year,
今回SSRBをグッズにさせていただきました。
and now SSRB is becoming merchandise!
獅白ぼたん 100万人記念 商品構成
Shishiro Botan 1 Million Commemoration Product Lineup
SSRB... 見ていきましょう。
SSRB... Let's take a look.
SSRB ぬいぐるみ
SSRB Plushie
SSRBぬいぐるみ、これね、
The SSRB plushie, you see,
ぬいぐるみ要望めちゃ多かったんですよ。
there were so many requests for a plushie.
なので今回ちょっと作らせていただきました。
So we decided to make one this time.
SSRB クッション 白
SSRB Cushion White
そして、SSRBのクッション、
And then, the SSRB cushions,
白と黒、ございます。
available in white and black.
SSRB クッション 黒
SSRB Cushion Black
ぜひ、ケツに敷いてください。
Please sit on them. (Wait, I shouldn't say 'butt')
ケツって言っちゃダメだ。
I shouldn't have said 'butt'.
尻に敷いてあげてください。
Please use them for your bottom.
獅白ぼたん オリジナルノート
Shishiro Botan Original Notebook
そして次、獅白ぼたんオリジナルノート。
And next, the Shishiro Botan original notebook.
こちら、イラストはあぁもんど先生と、
The illustrations are by Almond-sensei and...
SSRBの生みの親のMisa先生に
...SSRB's creator, Misa-sensei.
描いていただきましたので、
Since they drew them for us,
ぜひ勉強に、自由帳に
please use it for studying, as a diary,
お小遣い帳に、自由に使ってください。
or an account book—use it freely.
そしてですね、今回
And also, this time,
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
フル購入特典として、なんと書きます、
as a full set purchase bonus... check this out!
直筆サイン。直筆サインが入った、
A hand-signed... a hand-signed signature.
箔押し、メッセージは複製で
A foil-stamped postcard—the message is printed,
入れさせていただきますが、
but I'll be signing it...
サインは直筆で書かせていただきます。
...personally with my own hand.
こちらフルセットの購入者の特典と
This is a bonus for full set purchasers,
なっておりますので、ぜひぜひ
so I'd be happy if you consider buying it.
お買い求めいただけたら嬉しいです。販売がですね、
Sales start on...
100万人記念 フルセット
1 Million Commemoration Full Set
3月13日21時から、ホロライブの
...March 13th at 21:00, at the Hololive
公式グッズのショップでオープンしますので、
official goods shop, so please check it out.
3月13日販売開始
Sales Start on March 13th
ぜひよかったら買ってください。
Please get it if you'd like!
さあ、それでは最後、お待ちかねの
Now then, finally, the long-awaited...
アイドル衣装のお披露目です。
...idol costume reveal!
この配信のあとですね、
After this stream ends,
8時から公式チャンネルのほうでも
from 8:00, on the official channel,
ねぽらぼの配信があるので、そちらも
there's a NePoLaBo stream, so please
ぜひお楽しみください。
look forward to that as well.
それでは、獅白ぼたん、
And now, Shishiro Botan...
ライブステージへ行ってきます！
...is off to the live stage!
鳥の詩 / 歌：獅白ぼたん
Tori no Uta / Vocals: Shishiro Botan
消える飛行機雲
The vanishing contrails
僕たちは見送った
We watched them fade away
眩しくて逃げた
They were so bright we looked away
いつだって弱くて
Always being so weak
あの日から変わらず
Since that day, unchanging
いつまでも変わらずに
Forever remaining the same
いられなかったこと
The fact that I couldn't stay that way
悔しくて指を離す
Is frustrating, so I let go
あの鳥はまだ上手く
That bird still can't
飛べないけど
Fly very well yet
いつかは風を切って知る
But one day it will cut through the wind and know
届かない場所がまだ
The unreachable place
遠くにある
Is still far away
願いだけ秘めて見つめてる
I just gaze at it with a hidden wish
子供たちは
The children
夏の線路歩く
Walk along the summer tracks
吹く風に
In the blowing wind
素足をさらして
Exposing their bare feet
遠くには
In the distance
幼かった日々を
The childhood days
両手には
In their hands
飛び立つ希望を
The hope to take flight
消える飛行機雲
The vanishing contrails
追いかけて追いかけて
Chasing, chasing after them
この丘を越えた
Crossing over this hill
あの日から変わらず
Since that day, unchanging
いつまでも真っ直ぐに
Always being straightforward
僕たちはあるように
May we always remain that way
海神（わたつみ）のような
Like the god of the sea
強さを守れるよ きっと
I'm sure we can protect that strength
あの空を回る
Rotating in that sky
風車の羽根たちは
The blades of the windmill
いつまでも同じ夢見る
Always dream the same dream
届かない場所を
Looking at the place
ずっと見つめてる
That's out of reach
願いを秘めた鳥の夢を
A dream of a bird with a hidden wish
振り返る
Looking back
焼けた線路
At the sun-scorched tracks
入道雲 形を変えても
Cumulonimbus clouds, even if they change shape
僕らは
We...
僕らは 覚えていて
We will remember
どうか 季節が
Please, let the seasons...
残した昨日を
...the yesterday they left behind
消える飛行機雲
The vanishing contrail
追いかけて 追いかけて
Chasing it, chasing it
早すぎる合図
The signal that's too early
ふたり笑い出してる
The two of us start laughing
いつまでもまっすぐに
Always straight ahead
眼差しはあるように
May our gaze remain
汗が滲んでも
Even if sweat seeps through
手を離さないよ
I won't let go of your hand
ずっと
Forever
消える飛行機雲
The vanishing contrail
僕たちは見送った
We watched it go
眩しくて逃げた
It was so bright we ran away
いつだって弱くて
Always weak
あの日から変わらず
Unchanged since that day
いつまでも変わらずに
Forever unchanged
いられなかったこと
That we couldn't stay that way
悔しくて指を
Frustratedly, my fingers...
離す
...let go
獅白ぼたん アイドル衣装
Shishiro Botan: Idol Costume